

NOOR FAREEN ABDUL RAHIM

62-5-1 Seruan Emas Apartment, Solok Rawana, 10460 Penang Mobile: +60164429825, +60165249825 Email: fareen76@hotmail.com & noorfareen@uum.edu.my

Career Aim

As an experienced Senior Executive in the banking industry for more than 10 years, and a senior lecturer in a public university, my knowledge and experience could help the university to achieve its objectives. Able to work as part of the team and having the proven ability to successfully work to tight schedules and deadlines.

Area of Interest

Internal Control System, Enterprise Risk Management, Operational Risk Management, Banking Operations Management, Corporate Governance, Management Information System, Management Ethics, Customer Service and Relationship, Human Resource Management, Performance Management, Training and Consultancy, Education and Marketing.

Work Experience

- Teaching Management Information System and Management Ethics for undergraduate and postgraduate.
- Co-Supervisor for PhD students.
- Supervising Internship, Master by Research and Master by coursework students.
- Examiner for Master's Student Viva Voce and PhD student proposal defense.
- · Chairman for Master's Student Viva Voce

• Training Module Writer of Gourmet on Wheel Project for Cooperative Entrepreneurship and Development Institute, UUM

Reviewer:

- 1. 2016 International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management
- 2. Conference On Business And Management Research Discover UUM 2016

· Discussant:

- 1. 4th Symposium of Business Postgraduate Research.
- 2. 5th Symposium of Business Postgraduate Research.
- 3. 6th Symposium of Business Postgraduate Research.

• Committee Member:

- Industrial and Alumni Committee of School of Business Management, UUM.
- 2. Website Committee School of Business Management, UUM.
- 3. Welfare Committee School of Business Management, UUM.
- RHB Bank Senior Executive with experience in customer service and relationship with recognized strengths in banking operations department that includes current account department, remittance department, branch accounting system, electronic procurement, problem-solving and trouble-shooting of branch information system, and implementing procedures and systems to avoid problems in the first place. Good experience with branch operational risk management, corporate governance and internal control system.
- · Possess solid computer skills.
- Excellent working knowledge using Microsoft Excel, and Microsoft Word.
- Ability to train, motivate and supervise employees.
- A team player in managing branch queue system.
- Responsible for the departmental administrative tasks.
- Carrying out staff appraisals.
- · Prepared monthly reports for senior managers.

- Conduct fortnightly high risk audits, process branch accounting reports and filings, and maintain/update accurate inventories.
- Time management skills to ensure targets are met and plans completed efficiently.

Achievements (Bank)

- Improvement in branch internal audit rating report, from fair to satisfactory for year 2012.
- Increased in branch customer applications and acceptance of internet banking account management system.
- Increased in the application and usage of debit cards by individual and sole-proprietor accounts.
- Increased in branch individual and business customers opening of multi- currency account.
- Increased in local and foreign remittance transaction initiated by individual and business customers.
- Proactively managed branch queue system and lead to the improvement of branch achievement in customers waiting and serving time.
- Created customer awareness in managing and maintaining current account, drastically reducing the number of overdrawn current account holders.
- Increased of branch current and savings account deposits.

August 2010 to April 2011-Consultant and Trainer for HRSoft Management Consultancy

- Assist client in diversifying from current business of corporate training to education business. Includes:
- Train the client in doing comparative studies by:
- Shortlist 6 universities in Malaysia which are providing diploma courses as franchisors.
- Get the syllabus / course outlines from the 6 shortlisted universities.
- Conduct comparative studies analysis of the 6 shortlisted universities.
- Identify potential strategic partners based on the financial return and the need of courses among the factory workers in Penang.
- Successfully help the client by :

- 1) Identifying and initiate contacts with 6 potential strategic partners; Universiti Teknologi Tun Hussein Onn (UTHM), Asia E-University (AeU), Universiti Malaysia Sabah (UMS), Universiti Malaysia Pahang (UMP), Universiti Islam Antarabangsa Malaysia (IIUM) and Universiti Malaya (UM).
- 2) Initiate the establishment of network with UTHM and AeU.

Employment

Senior Lecturer School of Business Management

2015present

Universiti Utara Malaysia

1999 - 2015

RHB Bank Berhad Senior Executive

(Jalan Burmah branch 1999-2002 as a Junior Executive, Sungai Dua branch 2002-2012, Ayer Itam branch 2012-2015)

Education

Graduate School of Business, University 2009-2014 Science of Malaysia

Doctorate in Business Administration (DBA)

Dissertation Title: Antecedents and Outcomes of Perceived Operational Risk Management: Case of Local Conventional Banking Industry in Malaysia

School of Computer Science, University Science of 2002-2004 Malaysia

Master Science in Information Technology (MSc IT)

School of Management, Universiti Utara Malaysia 1996-1999 Bachelor in Human Resource Management (BHRM)

Publication

Article Published by American Science Publisher (Scopus)

(2014): Perceived Operational Risk Management and Customer Complaints in Malaysian Conventional Banking Industry (1st Author)

Article Published by International Journal of Business and Social Science (ISI) (2016): Charisma Leadership an Important Determinant for the Crisis Management (Co-Author)

Article Published by IRMM (Scopus) (2016): Moderating Effect of Growth Need Strength on the Relationship between Job Characteristics and Job Satisfaction (Co-Author) Article Published by International Journal of Supply Chain Management (Scopus) (2017): Internal Control System and Hazard Identification of Operational Risk in Malaysian Conventional Banking (1st Author)

Article in Proceedings:

- 1. Business Ethics and Operational Risk Management in Bank (1st Author) in 1st International Research Conference on Economics Business & Social Sciences at Holiday Inn, Penang, Malaysia, 12-13 April 2016
- 2. The influences of Halal Industry Macroenvironments on Export Performance: Mediating role of Marketing Program (2nd Author) in 1st International Research Conference on Economics Business & Social Sciences Sciences at Holiday Inn, Penang, Malaysia, 12-13 April 2016
- 3. Internal Control System and Perceived Operational Risk Management in Malaysian Conventional Banking Industry (1st Author) in 3rd Annual ECoFI Symposium (AES) 2016 at EDC Hotel, Kedah, Malaysia, 18 December 2016
- 4. Smart Living: Telecentre as the Basis for A Sustainable Rural Economy in Malaysia (2nd Author) in 3rd Annual ECoFI Symposium (AES) 2016 at EDC Hotel, Kedah, Malaysia, 18 December 2016

References

1. Professor Dato' Dr. Hasnah Haji Haron Dean

IPS

Universiti Malaysia Pahang

Contact Number: 012-4092755

2. Professor Dr. Krishnaswamy Jeyaraman

Senior Lecturer

Taylors University College Contact Number: 010-3750868